<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
   Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
  contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
  this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
  The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
  (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
  the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
   distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
   limitations under the License.
-->

<document>

 <properties>
  <title>Commons</title>
  <author email="dev@commons.apache.org">Commons Documentation Team</author>
 </properties>

 <body>

<section name="Commons EL">

<subsection name='What Is EL?'>
    <p>
    EL is the JSP 2.0 Expression Language Interpreter from Apache.
    </p>
</subsection>

<subsection name='What Is The JSP 2.0 Expression Language?'>
<p>
The JSP Standard Tag Library (JSTL), version 1.0, introduced the concept of an Expression Language (EL), whose main goal is to provide page authors with an easy way to access and manipulate application data without requiring the use of scriptlets 
</p>

<p>
JSP 2.0 adopted the EL specification from JSTL, and expanded its scope: EL expressions are no longer limited to JSTL action attributes, but may be used in any standard or custom action attribute declared to accept a runtime expression. In addition, EL expressions may now also be used directly in template text outside of any actions. JSP 2.0 also added an important feature to the EL specification: EL functions, which allow page authors to invoke static methods in Java classes from EL expressions. Additionally, JSP 2.0 allows programmatic access and customization of the EL evaluator through a set of standard interfaces and abstract classes. 
</p>
</subsection>

</section>


<section name="Documentation">

<p>The <a href="http://commons.apache.org/el/RELEASE-NOTES.txt">
Release Notes</a> document the new features and bug fixes that have been
included in the latest release.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://commons.apache.org/el/api/index.html">
JavaDoc API documents</a> for the latest release are available online.  
In particular, you should read the package overview of the <code>org.apache.commons.el</code> package.</p>

</section>


<section name="Releases">

<ul>
<li>Version 1.0 (from mirror) - 20 Jun 2003
    <a href="http://commons.apache.org/el/download_el.cgi">binary / source</a> (latest)</li>
</ul>

</section>


</body>
</document>
